Christina Fairbairn

1 Newport Crescent, Ottawa, Ontario K1T3L8 613-736-1504 / 613-983-1504 cfair0064@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a student of the Interactive Media Management Program at Algonquin College as well as a graduate of the University of Ottawa with a Bachelor of Arts Degree. Throughout my education and previous working experience I have worked diligently with clients and colleagues to obtain exemplary results.

I have two years experience in freelance multimedia content creation, one year full-time experience in second-language program delivery, as well as four years part-time experience in retail service delivery. I possess exceptional problem solving and time management skills, honed by my previous job experience. Spoken Languages include English (first language) and French at the intermediate level.

EXPERIENCE

Web Content Creator, Freelance

Aug 2016 - Present

- Created multi media content for the web including videos, voice overs, scripts, music, animations, and live-action film
- Collaborated with team members/clients to complete media projects
- Edited and finalized final drafts and submissions.

English Monitor, Odyssey/C.S. Kamouraska

Sept 2015-June 2016

- assisted in the delivery of a program to teach English as a second language
- prepared and presented English language activities for students in grades 2-6
- utilized "Team Teaching" strategies with resource teachers created a positive environment to facilitate learning experiences for students

Sales Associate, Babies RUS

June 2011-July 2015

- provided prompt service delivery to customers, tending to all customer concerns, both proactively and reactively responded to phone calls and processed sales transactions at register
- maintained a well organized and attractive display electronically updated and completed baby registries and online orders

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Video/Audio

- Adobe Premiere
- Adobe After Effects
 Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Audition
- Logic Pro X
- Audacity

Graphics/Layout

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe XD
- Microsoft Office Suite

Code/Editors

- CSS
- HTML5
- Sublime text
- Brackets

Hardware

- **DSLR Cameras**
- Condenser Microphones
- Audio Interfaces
- Tripods
- Light Kits
- Zoom Handy Recorders

EDUCATION

Interactive Media Management - Ontario College Graduate Certificate 2018-2019 (Anticipated Graduation Date: May 2019)

School of Media and Design | Algonquin College | Ottawa, ON

History Major/English Minor/French Immersion - Bachelor of Arts 2010-2015

Faculty of Arts | University of Ottawa | Ottawa, ON

INTERESTS

 Voice Acting, Writing, Animation, Video Games

ADDITIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

- Current 4.0 GPA (90%) at Algonquin College
- 8.0 GPA (80%)/ above maintained at University of Ottawa (2010–2015)
- Admission Scholarship (2010–2014)
- Immersion Study Scholarship (2010)

REFERENCES AND PORTFOLIO

Available upon request